DevOps Engineer

SANTOSH SUBEDI

Phone: (682) 999 84 73

Email: <u>ssubedi761@gmail.com</u>

Professional Summary

7+ years experienced AWS DevOps Engineer possessing in-depth experience of managing cloud-based technology & effectively handling configuration & deployment of infrastructure & services. Gained hands-on experience in implementing core DevOps concepts such as containerization, virtualization, version control, cloud computing, database management & administration, auto scaling, load balancing etc. by using a wide variety of technologies while working with multiple DBMS, Operating Systems & programming languages.

Skills

Work Environment: SDLC Agile, Scrum, Waterfall

Cloud Services: AWS, MS Azure, GCP

Build Tools: ANT, MAVEN

Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery: Jenkins, TFS

Web/Application Servers: Apache Tomcat, HTTP Server, Weblogic.

Bug Reporting Tools:JIRA, and Confluence.

Virtualization/Containerization Platforms: Virtual Box, Vagrant, Docker

Version Control: Git, Subversion

Logging & Monitoring : CloudTrail, CoudWatch, Splunk, Nagios

Configuration Management: Ansible, Chef, Puppet, Kubernatees

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows, UNIX

Infrastructure as Code (IaC): CloudFormation, Terraform

Database & Storage Management: RDS (MySQL, Aurora, Oracle PostgreSQL),

DynamoDB, S3, Glacier, Redshift, EBS, EFS.

Work Experience

AWS DevOps Engineer

IBM, IRVING, TX - October 2019 - Present

- Planned, deployed, monitored, and maintained Amazon AWS cloud infrastructure consisting of multiple EC2 Instances as required in the environment.
- Created CloudFormation templates to provision various AWS resources like EC2, ELB, ASG, ENI, S3, SNS, Security Groups etc.
- Created security groups, network ACLs, Internet Gateways, Route tables and Elastic Network Interface (ENI) to ensure a secure zone for organizations in AWS public cloud.
- Created monitors, alarms and notifications for EC2 hosts using Cloud Watch.
- Worked on Multiple AWS instances, set the security groups, Elastic Load Balancer and AMIs, Auto scaling to design cost effective, fault tolerant and highly available systems.
- Created S3 buckets and managed policies for S3 buckets and Utilized S3 bucket and Glacier for Archival storage and backup on AWS.
- Wrote Ansible playbooks to manage configurations and install packages on AWS instances using Jenkins.
- Implemented Continuous Integration using Jenkins and GitLab.

Environment: AWS (EC2, ELB, ASG, SNS, ENI, S3, CloudWatch, CloudFormation), IaaS, PaaS, IaC, Jenkins, GitLab, Jira, Unix/Linux, Shell scripting, Groovy.

AWS DevOps Engineer

GreenDot, La Jolla, CA - February 2017 - September 2019

- Planned, deployed, monitored, and maintained Amazon AWS cloud infrastructure consisting of multiple EC2 Instances as required in the environment.
- On boarded and migrated test and staging use cases for applications to AWS cloud with public and private IP ranges to increase development productivity by reducing test-run times.
- Created monitors, alarms and notifications for EC2 hosts using Cloud Watch.
- Automated Deployment of Java microservices into Docker Containers using Ansible and Jenkins.
- Implemented and maintained Chef Configuration management spanning several environments in VMware and the AWS cloud.
- Worked on Multiple AWS instances, set the security groups, Elastic Load Balancer and AMIs, Auto scaling to design cost effective, fault tolerant and highly available systems.
- Created S3 buckets and managed policies for S3 buckets and Utilized S3 bucket and Glacier for Archival storage and backup on AWS.
- Virtualized the servers using the Docker for the test environments and dev-environments needs. And, configuration automation using Docker containers.
- Wrote Ansible playbooks with Python SSH as a wrapper to manage configurations and the test playbooks on AWS instances using Python.
- Used Splunk and Nagios as a monitoring tool to identify and resolve infrastructure problems before they affect critical processes and worked on Splunk and Nagios Event handlers in case of automatic restart of failed applications and services.
- Well Versed with Configuring Access for inbound and outbound traffic RDS DB services, DynamoDB tables, EBS volumes to set alarms for notifications or automated actions.
- Implemented Continuous Integration using Jenkins and GIT.
- Developed build and deployment scripts using ANT and MAVEN as build tools in Jenkins to move from one environment to other environments.
- Configured and ensured connection to RDS database running on MySOL engines.

Environment: AWS (EC2, VPC, ELB, S3, RDS, Cloud Trail), GIT, EBS, Cloud watch, Terraform, Cloud Formation, Docker, Jira, AWS CLI, AWS Auto Scaling, Unix/Linux, Shell scripting.

DevOps Engineer

DXC Technologies, Dallas, Texas - September 2014 – January 2019

- Experience in Software Integration, Configuration, building, automating, managing and releasing code from one environment to another environment and deploying to servers
- Involved in supporting cloud instances running Linux and Windows on AWS, experience with Elastic IP, Security Groups and Virtual Private Cloud in AWS.
- Extensive experience on configuring Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, Amazon Elastic Load Balancing IAM and Security Groups in Public and Private Subnets in VPC and other services in the AWS.
- Managed network security using Load balancer, Auto-scaling, Security groups and NACL.
- Extensively worked on Jenkins CI/CD pipeline jobs for end-to-end automation to build, test and deliver artifacts and troubleshoot the build issue during the Jenkins build process.
- Implemented Jenkins Code Deploy plugin to deploy to AWS and used to automate the build process and deploy the application to Tomcat server.
- Used Cloud Front to deliver content from AWS edge locations to users, allowing for further reduction of load on front- end servers.
- Created Docker images using a Docker file, worked on Docker container snapshots, removing images and managing Docker volumes.
- Configured Docker container for branching purposes and Implemented Docker automation solution for Continuous Integration / Continuous Delivery model.
- Created and implemented chef cookbooks for deployment and used Chef Recipes to create a Deployment directly into Amazon EC2 instances.

- Developed Chef Cookbooks to manage system configuration and for Tomcat, MySQL, Windows applications and versioned them on GIT repositories and Chef Server.
- Implemented Kafka Security Features using SSL and without Kerberos. Further with more grain-fines Security I set up Kerberos to have users and groups this will enable more advanced security features.
- Installed RedHat Linux using kick-start and applying security polices for hardening the server based on company's policies.
- Created users, roles and groups using Identity Access Management (IAM) and attached the required policies.
- Performed Branching, Tagging, Release Activities on Version Control Tool GIT (GitHub).

Environment: AWS Cloud, AWS Lambda, EC2, Puppet, GitLab CI, GitHub, RedHat Linux 5.x/6.x, Windows 2008/2012, SVN, GitHub/BitBucket, Azure, Maven, Ruby, Shell scripts, Ant, Terraform, Splunk, Nagios, Sonar, Agile, IaaS, PaaS, SaaS, PowerShell, WebLogic, Apache Tomcat, JBOSS.

DevOps Engineer

DECISION TRUST, NEPAL- July 2013 - Jun 2014

- As DevOps/Build & Release Engineer extensively involved in release management, Environment Management, deployments, Continuous integration, Continuous deployment, Incident management, Version management.
- Supported services related to branch/merge/revert code on Git and SVN.
- Experienced using Jenkins as a full cycle continuous delivery tool involving package creation, distribution and deployment onto tomcat application servers via shell scripts embedded into Jenkins jobs.
- Hands on experience in Configuration Management using Ansible, CHEF and Puppet.
- Monitored Linux servers and applications via Splunk and Nagios.
- Worked on Docker and created docker images from scratch.
- Performed R&D on deploying the content cloud platform on AWS using EC2, S3, and EBS.
- Involved in configuring AWS EC2 instances on cloud platform using Ansible.
- Delivered monitoring solutions to measure uptime for scenarios, proactively captured system failures, digital certificate validation, and addressed them.

Environment: Jenkins, Git, Github, Ant, Maven, AWS, Ansible, Vagrant, Docker, Tomcat, Naigos, Python, Shell, ruby.

Education

Bachelors Degree in Business Studies(BBS) - Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal, Pass Year 2012.